==春秋字幕组荣誉出品==
=  www.cqbbs.net  =
= 迷恋Tiziano 翻译&校对=
知道吗 你很幸运
You're lucky, you know.
我很少让人进我的房间
I rarely allow anyone into my flat.
我知道 我知道 我知道
I know, I know, I know.
简居陋室
Humble digs.
我不是你想的那种"内裤猎人"
Not exactly what you'd call a "panty peeler."
懂我的意思吗
Do you know what I mean?
但它正适合我
But it suits me just fine.
老实说 我很少在自己的床上过夜
To be honest, I rarely spend a night in my own bed anyway.
瞧 这就是我的见解:
You see, here's my theory:
对多数女人来说 如果一个男人乐意付出
For most women, if a guy's a good provider
而且人也不错 那么没有六块腹肌也没什么
and generally a nice chap, six-pack abs really aren't a deal-breaker.
不过 也不绝对
On the flip side, however,
即使网络男朋友坐在你旁边
even though the PC boyfriend sat next to you
手搭在你的肩膀上 你也不会心动
with his arm slung around your shoulder will deny it...
其实他也不会心动 对男人而言 我们只关心F.B.B 那就是:
And he will deny it. For us boys, it's all about F.B.B.
脸蛋 胸脯 屁股
Face. Boobs. Bum.
我只是实话实说
I'm just being honest.
人家说衣服是国际通用语言
It's been said that clothes speak the international language.
我必须承认一点 我对时尚很追崇
And I have to admit, I'm a bit of a fashion whore.
不幸的是 我今天要去上班 所以我必须穿的低调一点
Unfortunately, today I've got work, and I have to tone it down a little bit,
但是 没问题 Gucci 去年的夏季大甩卖！
but that's all right. Gucci. End-of-summer sale.
很朴素 而且我能轻而易举得搭配
Very understated. And I can easily spice it up with...
什么 不 不 我知道你在想什么
What? No, no. I know what you are thinking.
如果你有阳刚气 就像我们这里的某人一样
If you ooze masculinity, like some of us do,
你没理由避开粉红色 帅呆了！
you have no reason to fear pink. Smashing.
现在 该撒古龙水了 很多男人用过头了
Now, in the cologne department, most men overdo it.
美国人通常是喷洒
Americans practically spray it on with a crop-duster.
我的原则：颈部以上不用
My rule: Nothing above the neck,
但是我却喜欢在我的大笨钟上面撒一点
though I do like a little splash on Big Ben.
你永远不会知道今天会发生什么
You never know where the day may take you.
差点忘了
Almost forgot.
每日一词
New word for the day.
"卖弄: 试图吸引别人注意力的行为"
"Ostentatious: The attempt to attract attention to oneself."
谁 我
Who? Me?
哦 我太失礼了 我还没介绍我自己
Oh, blimey. I'm so rude. I haven't introduced myself.
－我是...  －阿尔菲
－I'm... －Alfie
你知道了 阿尔菲
There you go. Alfie.
是你这个小精灵在我门前留的莫卡咖啡塘吗
Are you the little elf that left these mocha bonbons on my doorstep?
没有 一定是有人暗恋你 斯尼特莫太太
No, no, no. You must have a secret admirer, Mrs Schnitman.
你真可爱 阿尔菲 但是我应该节食
You are such a doll, Alfie. But I'm supposed to be on a diet.
哦 节食?
Oh, on a diet?
－节食? －您?
－A diet. －You?
－是的 －我不想说得太直接 露
－Yeah. －Now, I don't mean to be forward, Lu,
但您必须知道 像您这样丰满的女孩
but you should know by now that a full-figured girl like yourself
－是每个男人的梦想 - 别再说了
－is every guy's secret fantasy. －Stop it.
虽然她像一摊猪油 事已至此
So she's a tub of lard. The ship's already sailed,
那何不让她自我感觉良好一点呢 是吧
so why not make her feel good about herself, right?
－哦 对了 露 －是的 亲爱的
－Oh, Lu －Yes, angel
我今天上夜班
I'm working the night spot,
而我的房间里一团糟 不过我很不好意思总是让你
and my apartment is a horror show, so I'm sorry if I keep you up
－在下午两点帮我打扫一下 －哦 别担心
－with the dust－busting at 2 a.m. －Oh, don't you worry.
－我会很快帮你整理一下的 －不 不 您不必那样
－I'll give it a quick straighten. －Oh, no, no, you don't need to that.
别这么说 我乐意服侍你 阿尔菲
Nonsense. I like doing things for you, Alfie.
有你在我身边 我真是太幸福了
I'm a blessed man having you in my life.
谢谢你
Thank you.
钥匙在老地方
Keys are in the usual spot.
在家里你总是能听到一些人的传奇故事:
Now, back home, you're always hearing tales about some bloke
移民到美国 然后大把大把地捞钞票
migrating to the states and winding up with buckets of money.
所以不久前  我打点行囊 来到这里
So not long ago, I packed up my bucket and headed west.
我得承认 我有其他动机
Now, I must admit, I had a second motive.
人们都说世界上 最漂亮的女孩都
I'd always been told that the most beautiful women in the world...
...聚集在曼哈顿
...resided in Manhattan.
当你决定去搞女人时 只会关心一件事:
And when it comes to shagging birds, it's all about one thing:
地点 地点 地点
Location, location, location.
上帝 我爱死这座城市了 好啊 女孩们
God, I love this city. All right, girls.
看看周围 每个都那么独一无二 与众不同
Just look around. I mean, every one of them, unique, special,
就像雪花瓣
like snowflakes.
又是那么的丰盛...
And with such a plethora...
每日一词上的解释是"魅力十足 差异万千"
Calendar word meaning "abundance," of gorgeousness and diversity,
这样的话 一个男人怎么能 只想和一个女人厮守到老呢
well, how could a man ever choose to settle down with just one?
我本人更信奉欧式生活哲理:
I myself subscribe more to the European philosophy of life.
酒和女人永远是第一位的...
My priorities leaning towards wine, women...
事实上 人生就如此
Well, actually, that's about it.
酒和女人
Wine and women.
然而 在女人之间做选择 亦是一件乐事
Although, women and women is always a fun option.
所以
So...
...尽情地享受生活
...to live life to the fullest,
我只需应付日常的开销就足够
I require only enough to cover my modest expenses.
我不想成为墓地里最有钱的死尸
I've no desire to be the richest stiff in the cemetery.
我想这也许是我最喜爱的体位了
I think this might just be my favourite position.
我知道这是肯尼迪总统的招牌姿势
I know it was President Kennedy's.
他真是个潮流领导者
He was such a great leader.
当然 他只是用背伤作为藉口
Of course, JFK used the old bad-back excuse,
但我觉得 其实他知道 这个体位会给人最大的快感
but if you ask me, he knew it gave you maximum pleasure
用最小的付出
with minimum exertion.
加长轿车的后背座怎么样
What is it about the back of a limo?
不可推托的拥抱
Obligatory cuddling.
一千零一
Thousand one,
一千零二...
thousand two...
哦 嘿 我得走了 我十点要去接人
Cripes. Hey, I've gotta get cracking. I've got a 10:00 pickup.
你最好快点 你不会想让她久等的
You better hurry up. You don't want to keep her waiting.
还算不错吧
Quite the number, isn't she?
但是  她告诉我她老公 六个月没碰她了
Yet, she tells me her old man hasn't shagged her in six months.
六个月！我的意思是 感谢上帝 幸好还有像我这样的"绅士"在
Six months. I mean, thank God there are gentlemen like me around
来填补这个空挡
to pick up the slack.
看看她 像赛马般的腿
Just look at her. Legs like a racehorse.
完美的瑜伽身心 我给她打出了我的最高分:
Perfect yoga bum. I give her my highest grade:
A-
A-minus.
你怎么跟你老公说我们今晚去了哪
Where did we tell the old man we were going tonight?
－看电影 －宝贝  求你 别别这样
－A movie. －Treasure, please, no, no, no.
你把我的预设都打乱了
Stop messing about. You'll ruin my presets.
－抱歉 －看什么电影
－Sorry. －What movie?
我不知道 有什么区别吗
I don't know. What's the difference?
区别在于  你告诉他越详细 他就越不感兴趣
The difference is, the more detail you give, the less interested he'll be.
我说什么都无所谓
It wouldn't matter what I said.
菲儿决不会想到会有其他男人
It would never occur to Phil that another man
－会再看上我 －桃儿 亲爱的
－would ever look twice at me. －Dor, darling,
你想寻求恭维
you fishing for a compliment?
不是
No.
到现在 你应该知道 只有在最不经意间 我才会这样
You should know by now they only come from me when least expected.
吃块薄荷糖 这样菲尔就闻不到你的呼吸中有我的味道了
Now, come and have a mint so Phil doesn't smell the Alfie on your breath.
他闻到了我也不在乎
I don't care if he does.
只有一件事让我远离婚姻: 那就是已婚女人
There's one thing that puts me off marriage: It's married women.
桃利还不明白这个
Dorie doesn't know it yet,
但你不太会想再看到她了
but you won't be seeing much more of her.
我有点腻了的感觉
I've got that all-too-familiar feeling.
迟早 她会提出我满足不了的要求
Sooner or later, she'll be wanting a little bit more than I'm able to give.
今晚如果我跟你回家 而不是菲尔那个傻瓜
Wouldn't it be great if I was going home with you tonight
那不是很好吗
instead of Phil the Pill?
是啊
Yeah.
绝对是到玩消失的时间了
It's definitely time to stage a disappearing act.
那么下周二  老时间 老地方吗
So next Tuesday, same time, same place?
抱歉  亲爱的 那是时装周 我要轮班
I'm sorry, love, it's Fashion Week. I'm booked double shifts.
－我忙完就打电话给你 －好
－I'll call you the instant things let up. －Okay.
另外 我还留了一些小纪念品让你会想起我
In the meantime, I left you a little souvenir to remember me by.
哦 桃
Oh, Dor
你的臀部从这个角度看实在是很迷人
Your derriere looks really rather ravishing from this vantage point.
瞧
See?
出其不意的恭维
A compliment when least expected.
我说什么好呢 快乐得像个摇尾巴的小狗
What can I say? Happy as a pup with two tails.
而且我觉得也算帮了老菲儿一个小忙
And I think I've done old Phil a bit of a favour too.
当然 他肯定是最后一个知情的
Of course, he'd be the last to see it.
别指望此生能够得到任何人的报答
Never expect any thanks in this life.
你明白吗 那么下周二...
You know what I mean? So Tuesday...
...晚上10:03
...10:03 p.m.
我是该回我那冷冰冰的房间 空空如也的冰箱
Do I drag myself home to a cold flat, empty fridge,
还是快点回城里 享受热水澡 混暖的身体 在床上享用早餐呢
or nip across town for a hot bath, warm body, breakfast in bed?
做决定 做决定...
Decisions, decisions...
没错 我想该去看看我的半正式的
Yeah, I think I'll pay a visit to my semi-regular,
准女朋友
quasi, sort of girlfriend.
我的宝贝茱莉.
My sweet Julie.
让我猜猜 出乎意料的最后一刻她来找你
Let me guess. Unexpected last-minute fare.
是啊 她让我来来回回的开了几个小时
Yeah. She had me going up and down for hours.
那不是很有趣吗 因为那是如此...
That supposed to be funny? Because it is so very...
没趣
Not.
嗨!
Hey!
我不是开玩笑 阿尔菲!
I'm not kidding, Alfie!
我没开玩笑 有时侯我真的恨你
I'm not kidding. I hate you sometimes.
是啊 你懂得如何用炫耀的方式来表现出来
You have a very ostentatious way of showing it.
是 我当然会
Yeah, I sure do.
不 亲爱的 我们能停一下吗 我只想放松一下
No, darling. Can we hit pause? I just need a second to unwind.
哦,我从豪华轿车里偷了半瓶伏特加酒
Oh, I nicked half a bottle of Stoli from the limo.
你想怎么喝 加冰块吗
How do you want yours, on the rocks?
我就想像往常一样 阿尔菲 来吧
I just want my usual, Alfie. Straight up.
不 我已经精疲力尽了 我明天早上再补偿你
No, I'm so totally knackered. I'll make it up to you in the morning.
我保证
Cross my heart.
但是今晚  我只想好好的吃一顿 洗个热水澡
But tonight, all I'm good for is a bite to eat, hot bath
再好好地睡一觉
and a nice long sleep.
这里不是假日酒店 阿尔菲
You know, this isn't a Holiday Inn, Alfie.
你说什么
What's that again?
你今晚到底去哪儿了 说真的
Where were you tonight? Really?
你真该去开个餐馆 这真是太好吃了
You've got to open a restaurant. That's seriously delicious.
谢谢 阿尔菲 这只是辣椒而已
Thanks, Alfie. It's just chilli.
嗨
Hey.
来吧 看着我
A little eye contact, please.
我们之间真有感情
We have something here,
还是我只是你随叫随到的女人呢
or am I just a glorified booty call?
嗨
Hey.
其实她想说的是
Here's what she's really saying:
她想要我负责 意思是: 成为 "正式的"
She wants me to commit. Translation: Become "domestified."
在一生中依属与任何人都是个错误
Now, it doesn't do to become dependent on anybody in this life.
改变你的本性 那你就死定了
Change your nature, you're a dead man.
再来点红辣椒
Chilli, please.
不要误解我 她是很可爱
Don't get me wrong. She's adorable.
乖巧? 当然啦 但那就足够了吗
Cute? Absolutely. But is it ever enough?
我告诉你男人是什么 我们想要惊艳
I told you how we men are. We want showstoppers.
问题在于: 茱利叶还未惊艳到...
And the problem is, Julie hasn't got enough
足以让我当回事
of the superficial things that really matter.
－我不值你对我那么好 －是啊 也许真的是
－I don't deserve you. －Yeah, that's probably true.
我爱死你了
Too bad I love you.
谢谢 亲爱的
Thanks, babe.
－阿尔菲 阿尔菲 －怎么了
－Alfie, Alfie... －What?
你竟然对我说 "谢谢 亲爱的"
You're giving me the "Thanks, babe."
你就用"谢谢 亲爱的"来回答我！
You're giving me the "Thanks, baby."
－冷静点 －别让我冷静!
－Calm down. －Don't tell me to calm down!
－我知道你怎么想! －等等
－I know how you feel! －Wait a minute.
－你会吵醒...  －麦克斯
－You're gonna wake up... －Max.
嗨 小家伙 我们吵醒你了吗
Hey, little man. Did we wake you up?
是啊
Yes.
伙计们 吸取我的教训
Now, lads, learn from my mistake.
决不要跟单身妈妈交往
Never get involved with a single mum.
瞧 她们带着附属品
See, they come with accessories,
有些是...
some of which can be...
...不幸的 无法逃避的
...unfortunately, irresistible.
像刚才那一幕 提醒你我都是有保质期
Sights like that make you realize we all have an expiration date.
而女人的确比男人的保质期要短 不是吗
And women do have a shorter shelf life than men, don't they?
我认为这是茱利叶昨天发脾气的原因
I think that's what Julie was banging on about yesterday.
豪华轿车及司机
Elegant Limousine and Chauffeur.
我以此为生
This is where I make my reasonably honest living.
这狠狠地打击了优雅的定义 你觉得呢
Standards of elegance has taken quite a pounding, wouldn't you say?
我知道 相信我 这不过是一块踏脚石
I know. Believe me, it's merely a stepping stone.
现在只做着原地准备而已
Currently parked on one of those stepping stones
是我的好朋友 以及未来合伙人 马龙
is my best mate and future business partner, Marlon.
黑色 就像洛内迪的肤色
Black. Like Lonette's skin...
...我再也触碰不到了
...which I will never again touch.
恐怕 你看到的他 心情很不好
I'm afraid you're not meeting my man on top form.
瞧 马龙最近比较烦
See, Marlon's got a problem.
"恼人"的洛内迪
It's called Lonette.
前不久 她甩了他
And very recently, it dumped him.
哦 亲爱的 拜托 这次什么问题呢
Oh, dear. Come on, what was it this time?
凌晨三点 我在她门前乞求她
Three a.m. Begging, at her front door.
－有多醉 －呕吐了
－Level of inebriation? －Vomiting.
好 让我理顺一下 凌晨三点
Right. So let me get this straight. You were at her front door,
你在她家门口 边乞求 边呕吐
3 a.m. In the morning, begging and vomiting?
然后呢 她不为此感动吗
And what, she wasn't charmed by that?
阿尔菲 为什么2号车里的伏特加酒没了
Alfie? Why is there no Stoli in car number two?
我不知道
I've no idea.
我得好好地看着这个家伙了
I gotta watch this guy like a hawk.
这矮家伙名叫闻
That little chap's name is Wing.
我老板 这个烂企业的老板
My boss and owner of this tragic enterprise.
－好好擦车 －"老板的概念"只是在我和马龙
－Wipe that car good. －Owner, that is, till me and Marlon
搞到贷款 把这家公司从他手里买下来之前
swing a loan and buy it out from underneath his scrawny...
嗨 这里 鸟粪没擦掉
Hello. You miss bird shit.
闻
Wing.
他是个乱叫的疯子
He's barking mad.
看他和那个女人说话的样子
Check out the way he talks to the little woman.
她给了他青春 帮他做饭
She's given him her best years, cooked his chop suey,
帮他打理公司一切事务 我打赌 曾有一次
helped with the business, and I bet at one time he couldn't wait
他迫不及待地撕开她的和服 但看看现在的他
to rip off her kimono. And now look at him.
我开始怀疑起婚姻制度
And I'm supposed to respect the institution of marriage?
真是个好主意 我们搞到那笔贷款
That's a great figure, man. We swing that loan,
你从退休帐户上提钱 我当了摩托车
cash your IRA, I hock my Vespa...
那一定会让闻大吃一惊的
We're gonna take Wing by surprise with an offer like this.
我能预料到这些 瞧 马龙和洛内迪的感情到了
I could've predicted this. See, Marlon and Lonette have reached
这关键的"18个月"的危险时期 "我们的未来怎样 我们在干什么"
that critical 18-month "Where are we going, what are we doing,
"我们怎么了" 这些讨厌的问题
what's happening here?" crisis point that rears its ugly head
会出现在任何一段感情里 洛内迪想要结婚 家庭 孩子
in every relationship. Lonette wanted ring, home, baby.
马龙则还想要18个月
Marlon wanted another 18 months
以确定他不会遇上更好的
to make sure nothing better was coming his way.
我把事情搞砸了
I fucked up egregiously.
我看见你很茫然 不知所措
I see you're making the most of that birthday calendar.
等他意识到错误 希望她回到自己身边时...
By the time he realized he'd made a mistake and he wanted her back...
一切都太晚了 －嗨 陌生人
...it was too late. －Hey, stranger.
嗨
Hey.
...卡洛
Carol.
－卡洛!嗨 卡洛 －嗨
－Carol. Hi, Carol. －Hi.
你看上去棒极了
You look wonderful.
啊 卡洛 真高兴又见到你 你保重
So, Carol, well, it's nice to see you again. You be well.
刚才到底怎么回事
What's up with that?
这么说吧 戏才刚开场就结束了
Put it this way, the show closed after one performance only.
－我能知道为什么吗 －算了吧
－Do I even wanna know why? －No. Come on,
告诉你后就没意思了
it would be less than discreet to tell you why.
手臂上的毛 说真的 又粗又厚...
Hair on the arms. Seriously. Long, thick...
你在说什么 你手上没毛吗
What are you talking about? You don't have hair on your arms?
－你今晚看起来真漂亮 －谢谢
－You're looking very lovely tonight. －Thank you.
哦 吃闭门羹了 老兄
Dude, the iron door has slammed shut, man.
经典 不是吗
Classic, isn't it?
现在他得不到她 他觉得自己不能没有她
Now that he can't have her, he thinks he can't live without her.
有些人真是搞笑
Some people are funny.
马龙的尴尬处境让我想到我自己
Marlon's predicament got me thinking about my own situation.
或许...该是时候回家撩起欲火了
Maybe... Maybe it was time to stoke the home fires.
有人给小阿尔菲开门吗
Anybody in the mood for a little Alfie, straight up?
哦 阿尔菲 现在不是时候 我心里很乱
Oh, this isn't a good time, Alfie. Got a lot on my mind.
哦 上帝 是啊 我真的很讨厌那样
Oh, God. Yeah, I really hate when that happens.
开门 宝贝 你看上去美极了
Open up, baby. You look seriously beautiful.
－今晚不行 阿尔菲 －怎么了 告诉我
－Not tonight, Alfred. －What's the matter? Tell me.
我没什么...我只是... 我想我只是看到了
I don't... I'm just... Well, I guess I'm... I'm just...
我简直眼火爆
I'm just seeing red.
我是说 那个可怜人在痛不欲生
I mean, the poor guy, he's dying.
算了吧,难道你... 你已经折磨他很长时间了
Come on, haven't you...? You've tortured him long enough.
阿尔菲 他应该早料到这一天的
Alfie, he should've thought about all that
在他和他前女友搞不清楚之前
before he was screwing around with that ex-girlfriend of his.
那些假臀 廉价货色
Those fake-ass, $5 titties.
－那些是假的 －醒醒吧
－Those are fake? －Hello?
哇 我郁闷了 那些就像...
Wow, I'm devastated. They've got, like...
阿尔菲 你来这里该是来安抚我的 记得吗
Alfie, you're supposed to be consoling my devastation, remember?
我是 看他回心转意了 不是吗
I am. Look, he came back, didn't he?
双膝跪地 边乞求 边呕吐...
Begging, crawling on his knees, vomiting...
我不在乎
I don't care.
抱歉 我没那么好骗 而且我决不原谅他 也绝不会忘记
I'm sorry, I'm not that easy. I don't forgive and I definitely do not forget.
－我现在走行吗 小姐 －噢 是的 菲力克斯
－Is okay if I leave now, miss? －Oh, si, Felix.
顺道把灯关上 谢谢
And hit the lights on your way out, por favor.
我该走了
I better go.
外面要下大雨了
It's really coming down out there.
是啊
Yeah.
而且我穿着绒衣
And I'm wearing suede.
你得说真话 太好玩了
You're telling the truth. That's brilliant.
好吧 我想起来一个 我从没在太平洋里游过泳
Okay. I got one. I never swam in the Pacific Ocean.
－我也没有 －哦 该死
－Me neither. －Oh, shit. Okay.
哦 我从没看过一部007电影
Okay. I've never seen a James Bond movie.
你开玩笑 连肖恩.康纳里演的也没看过吗
You're joking. Not even a Sean Connery?
真的吗
You serious?
哇 不知道这到底算是奇迹还是悲剧
Wow, I don't know if that's magic or tragic.
好 五球 该我了
Okay. Five ball. My go.
－我从没自己铺过床 －哦 胡说
－I've never made my own bed. －Oh, bullshit.
不 我重复一遍 我从没自己铺过床
No, I repeat, I've never made my own bed.
哦 你有个什么样的妈妈啊
Well, what kind of mama you got?
问的好
That's a good question.
让我想想 恩
Let's see. All right.
－我告诉你一些事儿 －好
－I got something for you. －All right.
我从没做过...
I've never had sex...
我从未试过一晚上和两个人做过爱
I've never had sex with two people in one night.
五六个 你的最爱
Six-five, your favour.
懂了
Gotcha.
那么 阿尔菲 你一晚上最多和几个
So, Alfie, what's the most you've had in one night?
我们没在玩游戏是吗
We've stopped playing the game, haven't we?
是我理解错了 还是这里有人在调情挑逗
Am I wrong, or is there a little innocent flirting going on here?
伴随记忆
Driftin' on a memory
我只想同你寻觅
Ain't no place I'd rather be than with you
爱着你
Loving you
瞧 如果我有你这样的天分
See, if I had that kind of talent...
这首歌
And a song
－说 继续说完 －如果我有你那样的天分
－Go on, finish your sentence. －If I had that kind of talent,
那样的身材
and I looked like you...
这首歌
And a song
－...我就会展露我性感的一面 －哦 是吗 －在舞台上
...I would be strutting my stuff －Oh, yeah? －On a stage.
相信我 接下来发生的事是我
Trust me, what happens next was the furthest thing from my mind
今晚来时想也没想过的
when I dropped by tonight.
然而 我对自己说
But then I thought to myself,
知道吗
"You know what?
如果这能使她不再对马龙恼火
If this will help her get past her anger towards Marlon,
这应该作为我对朋友的义务 不是吗
I owe it to both of them, as a friend, right?
尽我所能的帮助他们
To do whatever I can to help."
我后来才发现
I find that, lately,
即使对自己撒谎 也是那么的容易
even lying to myself comes easily.
第二天早上 我一直无法忘却昨晚的事
The next morning, and I can't get last night out of my mind.
竭尽全力把注意力转移到别的事情上 任何别的事
Try desperately to focus on something else, anything else.
极力不再去想我好友妻子那性感到难以置信
Anything to get my mind off my best friend's incredibly hot,
我一生之中从未见过的完美臀部
best-ass-I've-ever-seen-in-my-life girlfriend.
阿尔菲 阿尔菲
Alfie. Alfie.
－阿尔菲！ －我该装做没听见吗
－Alfie! －Shall I pretend I can't hear him?
伙计
Dude.
－嗨 －要迟到了 要迟到了
－Hey! －Too late. Too late.
－嗨 你慢点 行吗 －嗨 马利 干嘛啊
－Dude, would you slow down? －Hey, Marly, what's up?
马力?
"Marly"?
嗨 听着 我得跟你谈谈 你先哪也别去
Hey, listen, I gotta talk to you. You ain't going nowhere
你得告诉我昨晚怎么样了
till you tell me what went down last night.
－昨晚? －是 别敷衍我了
－Down last night? －Dude, don't mess with me.
洛内特怎么了
What happened with Lonette?
你听过"敲门"这个词吗
Have you ever heard the word "knock"?
－怎么了 －什么 没事啊 没事发生
－What went down? －What? Nothing happened.
－我们打了几杆桌球 －老婆在对我冷战
－We had a few shots. －Missus give me silent treatment.
她就不知道 她不说废话那就是上帝保佑了
Little she know, not hearing constant "blah, blah, blah" is gift from heaven.
继续说 继续说 老兄 那有用
You keep it up. Keep it up, mate, it'll work.
阿尔菲 发生什么了
Alfie, what happened?
哦 真他妈的 老兄 瞧 我
Oh, fuck a duck, man. Look, I...
－我昨晚多喝了几杯 －醉了吗
－I drank a lot last night. －Drunk.
恩 我...
Well, I...
我真的...想不起来了
I really... I don't remember.
- 伙计,你一定对她做了些什么 - 没有
－Dude, you did something to her. －No.
哦,得了,你做了 因为今天凌晨四点
Oh, yeah, you did. Because she shows up at my house,
她来我家了 说她希望回到我身边
at 4 in the morning, saying that she wanted me back.
她甚至还说如果我想要更多时间考虑
She even said that if I needed more time,
她完全能理解
that she understood completely.
真他妈神了
How fucking crazy.
这家伙走运了 幸亏有我 马龙赢了
Chalk one up for the blokes. Thanks to me, Marlon won the game.
这意味着他将无罪释放 而我也是
Which means he's off scot-free, and so am I.
这真是个奇迹 太神了 太神了
This is a bloody miracle. That's fantastic. Fantastic.
－拜托 你是怎么对她说的 - 等等
－Come on, what did you say to her? －Look, look.
－一切很顺利啊 －嗨 你到底说什么了
－It's all good. －Come on, what did you say?
我向她求婚了
I asked her to marry me.
你是我最好的兄弟 是吗
You know you're my best man, right?
这个故事的寓意
Moral of the story
万事终有报！
No good deed goes unpunished.
今天的每日一词吗
New word for the day?
"恢复"
"Resilience:
从失望和失败中迅速痊愈的能力
The ability to readily recover after disappointment or loss."
反弹的能力
Capacity to spring back.
明白吗 我不是说为茱利找个替代品
Understand, it's not about replacing Julie.
我只是想回到简单的生活状态
I just wanna get back to the simple life.
女人对我毫无意义
Women who mean nothing to me.
所以我和个叫呜塔的酒吧招待 开始了一段友谊
So I've struck up a friendship with a nightclub hostess called Uta.
嗨 呜塔
Hello, Uta.
现在 作为一个追求刺激的单身汉
Now, as a heat-seeking bachelor,
我必须遵循一些简单的原则
I have to live by some very simple rules.
阿尔菲.鄂尔肯斯的信条 哲学
Alfie Elkins' credo or philosophy,
也可能是我父亲给我的唯一
which is probably best summed up by the only advice
忠告
my father ever gave me.
他说："儿子 当你看见一个漂亮姑娘...
He said, "Son, whenever you meet a beautiful woman...
记着 在别处一定有个男人已经厌烦了她"
...just remember, somewhere there's a bloke who's sick of shagging her."
－你要什么 －G&T(调和酒) 谢谢
－Can I help you, man? －G and T, please.
告诉我觉得那个欧洲痞子怎么样
Explain to me what everyone sees in that Eurotrash?
我觉得在性体验方面非常不公 男人可以比女人
I think it's incredibly unfair that it's acceptable for men
更放荡 而对于女人
to be sexually experimental, then with a woman,
如果她想要尝试下...比如接吻 三人行
if she wants to try something... A kiss or a threesome.
你知道的 就会有人说三道四 我就不会批判她们
You know, that they'd be judged. I wouldn't judge them.
我觉得如果你俩要接吻 我...我会
And I think if you two were to kiss, I would... I would just...
我会把它看做是一件美好的事
I would just see it as a thing of beauty.
尽管我像很多男人一样生活放荡
Although I'm living every guy's Rat Pack fantasy,
有些事我还是接受不了
something feels a bit off.
并且让我回到了从前的生活状态
And throwing myself back into the old lifestyle
而且不像我想象中的那么顺畅
isn't going quite as smoothly as I'd hoped.
抱歉
Sorry.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你们继续 别管我
You carry on without me.
噢 亲爱的 我...
Oh, my loves, I...
我不知道怎么回事 平时不是这样的
I don't know what happened. This is so unlike me.
对 你们... 你们还是...
Yeah, you... You two just...
我曾以为没有比死亡更糟糕的事了
I used to think there was nothing worse than death.
然而 无从解释...
Then, from out of nowhere...
无法想象的
...the unthinkable.
现在我真不知道别人会怎么看你
Now I really don't get what everyone sees in you.
这状况总是不断地出现 一次又一次
It just keeps on happening and happening.
或者更确切地说 没反应 又继续没反应
Or more accurately, not happening and not happening.
这从来未试过 呜塔 相信我 从没有
This never happens, Uta. Honestly, never.
真的
Honestly.
浪得虚名..
Not the word around town...
"短小精干"
...peewee.
鄂尔肯斯先生 我叫米兰达.库尔浦
Mr Elkins? Miranda Kulp.
米兰达
Miranda.
这个阴茎医生有点娘娘腔
The penis doctor is a he with a little bit of she thrown in.
我了解到你有ED (阳痿的术语)
So I understand you're experiencing some erectile dysfunction.
是 我是有点 有点...你刚才说的那个
I am experiencing a little... A little... A little bit of... What you just said.
别担心 我是这方面的专家
Not to worry. That's my area of expertise.
那么 你最近有否经历不寻常的情感压力 鄂尔肯斯先生
So have you been under any unusual emotional stress lately, Mr Elkins?
压力? 感情上的? 我? 不 从没
Stress? Emotional? Me? No, never.
当然 除非你把我最近和茱利的谈话也算在内的话
Well, unless you count that recent chat I had with Julie.
我不能再见你了 阿尔菲
I can't see you anymore, Alfie.
－怎么了 你生气了 －不 真我没有
－Why? You angry? －No, I'm really not angry.
只是 你知道的 我们所追求的不一样
Just, you know, we want different things.
我不能让你在麦克斯的生活中 时不时地出现消失
And I can't have you traipsing in and out of Max's life.
你换发型了 是吗
You've changed your hair, haven't you?
不是吗 不 你换了
You have, haven't you? No, you have.
你是换了发型 你剪短了
You've changed your hairdo. You cut it?
看上去漂亮极了
It looks gorgeous.
－谢谢 －为什么
－Thanks. －How come...?
为什么我们在一起的时候 你从不梳这样的发型
How come you never had it like that when we were together?
我必须得走了
I really gotta go.
哦 我想
Well, I guess...
你得要回这个
...you need these back.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿尔菲
Alfie?
你会没事的 对吗
You gonna be okay?
是的 别担心 我总是很好
Yeah. No worries. I'm always okay.
好吧 我们来检查下你的阴茎
Alrighty, let's take a gander at that penis of yours.
明白
I see.
好
Well.
－看来我们让它有反应了 －好像是啊
－It seems we have lift－off. －It seems we do.
真好
Wunderschon.
这下放心了
What a relief.
我是指 如果他都能让我起来 那我的生育大计
Well, I mean, if he can give me a stiffy, I should have no problem
就应该没问题了 是吧
keeping it up for the target demographic, shouldn't I?
恩 看来生理上没什么问题
Well, there doesn't appear to be anything physiologically wrong,
所以 简而言之 我们可以较为肯定的说
so, in short, we can be fairly certain your problem
－你的问题和压抑有关 －意思是：和茱利有关
－was simply stress－related. －Translation: Julie-related.
就像我常说的 事情不再朝一个方向发展时 那就会朝着反方向发展
Like I always say, if they don't get you one way, they'll get you another.
然而
However,
－我还是发现一些奇怪的东西 －奇怪的东西
－I did feel something a little kooky. －Kooky?
不用过分担心 鄂尔肯斯先生
There is nothing to get upset about, Mr Elkins.
我想你可能有一个肿块...
I thought I felt a lump...
...在你的阴茎上
...on your penis.
如果幸运的话 这不算什么
But with any luck, it will be nothing.
"肿瘤"和"阴茎"出现在同一个句子中
The words "lump" and "penis" in the same sentence.
这可不是每天都能听到的
There's something you don't hear every day.
小阿尔菲获得了一份提前的圣诞礼物
And so young Alfred got an early Yuletide gift.
阴茎活组织切除
A penis biopsy.
我会在三天内得到检查结果... 哦 是五天
I get my test results in three days... Well, five.
天哪 五天 五天后就是周末了 哦 主啊
Five counting the weekend. Oh, Lord. Oh, Lord.
我该怎么才能让自己不发疯呢
How am I gonna stop myself going completely bonkers?
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
我还年轻
I'm a young man.
转移注意力 阿尔菲 转移...
Shift focus, Alfie. Shift...
孩子们 我们走
Let's go, kids. Let's go.
向前走 孩子们 看正前方
Move along, children. Look straight ahead.
别看前面的陌生人 看正前方
Come on. Do not look at the man. Look straight ahead.
此时 我也许还是呆在家里好些
In the meantime, perhaps I'm safer hobbling on home.
阿尔菲 亲爱的 怎么了 你就像死而复生般
Alfie, dear, what's wrong? You look like death warmed over.
没 没 我只是 踢球时受了点伤 没事
No, I've just... I've got a bit of a football injury, that's all,
斯尼特莫太太您好 里贝曼太太 您好
Mrs Schnitman... Hello, Mrs Liberman.
你们看上去好极了 你们去哪
You two look lovely. Where you going?
－买东西 你要带什么吗 －不 不需要
－Shopping. You need anything? －I'm fine.
嗨
Hello.
能谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a minute?
女士们 这是我朋友洛内特
Ladies, this is my friend Lonette.
她真可爱 不错啊 和黑人约会
She's lovely. Good for you, dating an African-American.
是啊
Yeah.
嗨 嗨 亲爱的 我想你
Hey. Hey, girl. I missed you.
别理我们 当我们不在 你们继续说
Don't mind us. We're not here. You kids keep talking.
－很高兴见到你们 －再见 里贝曼太太
－Very nice to meet you. －See you, Mrs Liberman.
女士们 买到拿不动为止！
Shop till you drop, girls.
你最近好吗
So how have you been?
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
对我来说
It seems to me
那些我担忧的问题看来都是杞人忧天
the problems you worry yourself sick about never seem to materialize.
真正的问题却出乎意料
It's the ones that catch you unexpectedly
在一个周三的下午 犹如当头一棒
on a Wednesday afternoon that knock you sideways.
我提出和她共度难关...
I offered to face the music with her...
...但她想独自承受
...but she wanted to go it alone.
我们都知道如果这个孩子 出生时有任何白人特征
We both knew that if the baby was born with any white-boy features
洛内特和马龙就完了
it would mean the end of Lonette and Marlon.
更别提你们今晚的主角了
Not to mention your host for this evening.
但是站在寒风中 我感到自己心存愧疚
But standing in the cold, I find myself having regrets.
思绪袭来
Thinking thoughts like,
"又失去一个没有机会相识的孩子
"Here's another kid you'll never get a chance to know.
你的孩子"
Your own."
很快啊
Didn't take long.
天啊 你快冻僵了
Bloody hell, you're freezing.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
空虚
Empty.
那晚在酒吧 我以为我是顺手牵羊的
That night in the bar, I thought I was getting something for nothing.
没想过会搞成这样的 不是吗
Doesn't seem to have worked out that way, does it?
哦 天哪
Oh, man.
如果可以安然度过的话 或许这次与死亡擦肩而过
If everything turns out okay, maybe this little brush with mortality
只是个征兆
is a sign.
我该考虑做... 做一些改变了
I should think about making... Making some changes.
也许
Possibly.
－下周 －抱歉
－Next week. －Excuse me.
我刚是否...你是否刚看了我一眼 我留意到了你又躲开了
Did I just...? Did you just look at me? Did I just notice you turn away?
如果你知道了我的检查结果 他们告诉你了的话...
Look, if you know the results to my tests, and they're telling you...
－鄂尔肯斯先生 －求你 求你
－Mr Elkins. －Please. Please.
鄂尔肯斯先生 我说了一万遍了 请你坐回去
Mr Elkins, for the millionth time, sit down.
鲍尔逊先生 您周二11：30的预约取消了
Mr Belson, I have a cancellation on Tuesday at 11:30.
我会没事的
I'm gonna be fine.
－我觉得是这样的 －谢谢 再见
－I just feel it. －Thank you. Goodbye.
一分钟就好 或者十分钟
I'll just be a minute. Or ten.
－没关系 您慢慢来 －我没办法
－It's all right. Take your time. －I don't have a choice.
我以前是小便 现在我是在滴水
I used to pee. Now I trickle.
－我叫乔 你呢 －阿尔菲
－I'm Joe. What's your name? －Alfie.
你过得如何 阿尔菲
So how you doing, Alfie?
－等着呢 你呢 －不爽
－Hanging in. You? －Shitty.
是啊 我也一样 一样
Yeah, me too. Me too.
－我喜欢你的领带 －哦 谢谢 我我有一套
－I like the bolo tie. －Oh, thanks. I have a collection.
你晓得 到你老了 你就会懂得耐心
You know, when you're old, you learn to be patient.
是啊
Yeah.
过去我从没耐心去等 总是往前冲 冲啊 冲
Used to be I never had time for nothing. Go, go, go.
－我懂那种感觉 －是啊
－I know that feeling. －Yeah.
我妻子总是嚷着让我带她 去夏威夷 里诺渡假
My wife was always hawking me to take a little vacation. Hawaii. Reno.
我总是说 明年吧 爱维 明年
I always said, "Next year, Evie, next year.
我有很多事没做
I got too much on my platter."
我总以为我时间很多
I always thought I'd have more time.
然而一个周日的晚上 她从烤箱里取出烤肉
Then one Sunday night, she takes the pot roast out of the oven.
叫着 "汤来了" 但是重重地摔倒在厨房的地上
Yells, "Soup's on," and slumps to the kitchen floor.
就那样
Just like that.
就像迪斯科的衰亡
Dead as disco.
天啊 我很遗憾
Jesus, I'm sorry.
我试着拼凑过去的回忆
I tried picking up the pieces.
甚至独自去了淮基基海滩的8日游
Even went to Waikiki alone on the 8-day cruise package
就是她终日提起的那个
she was always yakking about.
爱维让我难以忘怀
Couldn't get Evie out of my mind.
孩子 生活教会了我两样东西:
There's two things I learned in life, kid:
找到自己的真爱
You find someone to love,
还有 把每天都当做你的末日来过
and live every day as though it were your last.
她是你的了 阿尔菲
She's all yours, Alfie.
享受吧
Enjoy.
你没事吧 孩子
You all right, son?
恩 希望如此
Yeah. I hope so.
瞧 如果你觉得无聊了 或者想找人聊天
Look, if you ever get bored or feel like schmoozing...
...可以向我倾诉
...give me a holler.
－你不会打的 －也许会的
－You'll never call. －Maybe I will.
好啊 不错 我们可以一起去酒吧 约会女孩子
All right, good. We'll go to a bar together, hit on some chicks.
没错
Damn right.
谢谢你 乔
Thanks, Joe.
嗨
Hey.
对于艾维的事我感到难过
I'm sorry about Evie.
我们...
We...
...我们并不是那么情投意合的...
...weren't all that fond of each other...
但我们很亲密
...but we were very close.
－如果你能明白我的意思 －我想我明白
－If you know what I mean. －I think I do.
最近我想了很多关于上帝和死亡的事
I've been thinking a lot lately about God and death.
如果圣经课上讲的都是真理
And how, if what they taught me in Bible class is true,
那我可就惨了
I'm really in for it.
不过就目前看 我还不会和撒旦为伴
But I won't be partying with Lucifer any time soon,
因为我的检查结果是阴性！
because my test results were negative.
我能活了！我能活下去了！
I'm gonna live! I'm gonna live!
我弄坏了我的Prada鞋 但我不在乎
I ruined my Prada lace-ups and I don't care.
别以为我忘了 我要彻底改变生活的誓言
Don't think I've forgotten my oath to completely change my life,
因为我没忘记
because I haven't.
胡萝卜苹果汁加点小麦草
Carrot-apple with a dash of wheat grass.
没错
Yep.
现在 健康是第一位的
Health is now priority number one.
工作计划正在步入高峰
Business plan moves onto the fast track.
－如果你这么说... －今晚在安布罗斯的预演...
－If you say so... －Tonight's preview at St. Ambrose...
不 我当然不想说啦 等等 我还有什么
No, I definitely don't want to talk. Okay, hold on, what else have I got?
对 好
Okay, yeah.
好吧 如果我们一定要 那就要吧 但是...
All right, if we must, we must, but...
新的目标 新的开始
New slate. New beginning.
－司机 你叫什么 －阿尔菲 先生
－What's your name, driver? －Alfie, sir.
在这等着 阿尔菲
Wait here, Alfie.
你知道大概要等多长时间吗
Do you know how long you're gonna be, roughly?
－你要到别的地方去 －不 不 我只是想转转活动一下
－You got someplace to go? －No, I was just gonna nip off
－喝杯茶 －那还不如原地待命
－and get a cup of tea. －Look, why don't you just stay put.
好 还是不好
Yea or nay?
好 当然好 我这么认为 真的
A definite yea, I think. Really.
太美了 您不这样认为吗 先生
Stunning. Wouldn't you say so, sir?
抱歉 难道我没让你在车旁等着吗
I'm sorry, didn't I ask you to wait by the car?
我想我该帮助这位女士提包
I reckoned I should help the lady with her packages.
真的好看吗
Definite yea?
我是这么认为的
I think.
一点小问题...
With one minor...
－可以吗 －是的
－May I? －You may.
调整一下
Adjustment.
斗牛士 别指望 下辈子吧
Bullfighter. Another lifetime. Don't ask.
50岁 看上去
Fifty, if she's a day.
但是他们不是说50就意味着女人的第二春吗
But don't they say 50 is the new 40,
难道她不是个活生生的例子吗
and is she not living proof?
我指 看看她 保养的多么好
I mean, have a look. Beautifully preserved.
乳沟像荷兰隧道
And cleavage like the Holland Tunnel.
－好些了吗 －好多了
－Better? －Much.
你选择Chanel真是太有眼光了 再来双性感的粉红高跟鞋
You are so right to trust Chanel. A pair of hot-pink stilettos,
你就可以闪亮登场了
and you're good to go.
－啊 你真是个全职的服务生 －我们尽量
－Well, aren't you Mr Full-Service? －We try.
－他有点生气了吧 －哦 没事 这对他有好处
－He's getting a little pissy, isn't he? －Oh, it's fine. It's good for him.
－你的丈夫比你大很多吧 －他不是我丈夫
－Is your husband a lot older than you? －He's not my husband.
他戴着结婚戒指
He's wearing a wedding ring.
我可从没说过他不是别人的丈夫
Well, I never said he wasn't somebody else's husband.
－后备箱里的东西拿出来 －遵命
－Grab the stuff from the trunk －You got it.
很好
Cheers.
女士 如果你以后需要我的服务
Ma'am, if you require my services in the future.
圣诞快乐 女士先生
Happy Christmas, sir. Ma'am.
看看 我的朋友们 那是个真正的女人
Now that, my friends, is a real woman.
聪明 性感 而且...
Smart and sexy and...
你注意到我们之间的短暂调情吗
You noticed the little flirt going on between us, huh?
让我想想
Makes me think,
像这样的女人
if a woman like that, of that calibre
看上我这样一个人
should take notice of a bloke like me,
然后 也许...
then, perhaps...
也许 我太低估我自己了
Perhaps I'm selling myself a bit short.
突然
In a flash,
我有了我的新年决心
I have my New Year's resolution.
更高的目标
Aim higher.
灾难性的. 厄运
Catastrophic. Doomed.
凄凉 大变更
Desolate. Cataclysmic.
买给他一本一日一词做圣诞礼物
Bought him a word-of-the-day calendar for Christmas.
大错特错
Big mistake.
节假日 一年中最大的商机
Holiday season, busiest time of the year.
我努力做生意
I try to run a business.
－怎么了 出什么事了 闻先生 －你的黑人兄弟
－What's the problem, Mr Wing? －Your soul brother.
他辞职了
He quit.
在马龙留给我的信里面 他称我为他的最好的朋友
In the letter Marlon left me, he called me his best friend...
但是为取消了我们的生意计划而道歉
...but apologized for bailing on our business scheme.
他说他现在最想做的事就是让洛内迪开心
He said his whole thing now was to make Lonette happy.
他们突然决定
They decided, on the spur of the moment,
要搬到北部去
to move upstate,
还随时欢迎我去做客
and I had a standing invite to drop by any time.
也许 洛内迪说服了马龙
Somehow Lonette convinced Marlon
我们当面说再见 会是件很痛苦的事
it would be too painful to say our goodbyes in person.
并且会使事情更糟
And to make matters worse,
又是每年第二个最寂寞的夜晚
it all dovetails into the second loneliest night of the year?
圣诞夜
Christmas Eve.
一个有着所有熟悉的节日气氛的夜晚
A night that brings on all those familiar festive feelings
无助 郁闷 绝望
of hopelessness, anguish, despair.
不是一个适合独处的日子
Not a great time to be flying solo.
这就是我坚持情侣是不应该在
That's why I'm of the belief couples should never split up
感恩节和1月2日之间分开的原因
between Thanksgiving and January 2nd.
总是保持着一段关系 来帮助你度过那些节日 一直如是
Always have a relationship to see you through the holidays. Always.
不好的是 当然 那就是要送礼物
The downside, of course, being gifts.
我总是怀疑其他人都
Personally, I've always suspected that everyone else
过着比我快乐的圣诞
is having a far merrier Christmas than I am.
不是说我从没真正过过圣诞
Not that I've ever actually had a Christmas.
那是另一部迪更斯小说的情节
That's a whole other Dickens story.
出租车
Taxi.
劳驾
Excuse me.
抱歉 兄弟 超载是违法的...
I'm sorry, mate, it's against the law for me to carry any more than...
感谢上帝
Thank the Lord.
圣诞奇迹
A Christmas miracle.
好吧 上来吧
All right, hop in.
谢谢你救了我们 我都快冻僵了
Thanks for saving us. I was freezing my little tush off.
别担心 你瞧 我后面已经坐满了
No worries. You know, it's pretty full back there.
－为什么你不... －好主意
－Why don't you... －Good idea.
为何不呢
Why don't I?
嗨 小心香槟
Hey, watch the champagne.
都上来啦
All in.
－他们不会太离谱的 －大家留点神
－They don't get out much. －You wanna watch out, you guys.
不然你们的圣诞袜子里的礼物会变成一块煤块的
You'll end up with a lump of coal in your stocking.
你是英国人
You're English.
我喜欢英国人
I love English.
－你叫什么 －阿尔菲
－What's your name? －Alfie.
想吸一口吗 阿尔菲
You wanna abuse a little substance, Alfie?
不 谢谢 我正想戒掉
No, thanks. I'm trying to quit.
好吧 就一口
All right. One hit.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmastime
美国佬有个谚语"随波逐流"
There's an expression the Yanks use, "Go with the flow."
哦 是的 我是有点假期忧郁症
So, yeah, I got a dose of the holiday blues.
但是当这样一个让你 意乱情迷的女孩邀你参加派对时
But when a girl of this mind-blowing calibre invites you to a party,
是时候该随波逐流了
it's time to get going and start flowing.
也许是来的太晚了
Maybe it's the late hour.
也许是蛋青酒太烈了
Maybe it's the heavily spiked eggnog.
也许是相互间狂野的欲望
Maybe it was simply a mutual desperate desire
带给了我们一个快乐的小圣诞
to have ourselves a merry little Christmas.
无论如何 勾引从未如此顺利
Whatever the reason, hooking up has never gone more swimmingly,
我发现我开始说出一些 不像我自己风格的话
and I find myself saying something highly out of character?
我正在翻修我在曼哈顿西区的房子
I'm renovating my apartment on the Upper West Side.
但是 如果 你
But, say, you could...
愿意将就去我暂租的房子 如果你愿意的话
...crash at my sublet, if you want.
整个假日都看到你
See you through the holidays.
听起来很诱人啊！
That sounds inviting.
那么多年来 终于时来运转了
And so it came to pass, that after all those years,
小阿尔菲终于在圣诞得到了他想要的
little Alfred finally got what he wanted for Christmas.
圣诞假期的12天飞逝
The 12 days of Christmas were flying by
如此的超现实
at a surrealistic pace.
是的 这样的兜风很爽
Yeah, it's been quite the ride.
这份"礼物"是难以抗拒的
The package was irresistible.
一次和性感学生妹的完美演出
A showstopper with a new-school brand of sexiness.
她回头时 谁会不驻足观望呢
Who wouldn't get off on the way she makes heads turn?
再且 我们有如此之多的共同点
Plus, we have so much in common.
－她是那么甜美 有趣 个性出众 令人兴奋 －爱慕着你
－She's sweet, fun, original, exciting, －Adore you.
充满了惊喜
Full of surprises.
哦 我差点忘了提了 她在床上棒极了
Oh, and did I mention, she makes a cracking good bed.
我开始想
I began to wonder,
这就是我要的那个...
could this be the one...
那个最终吸引我的人
...who finally holds my attention?
新年快乐
Happy New Year!
在每一段注定完蛋的感情中
In every doomed relationship,
总会出现那种我称之为的
there comes what I like to call
"阿呃时刻"
"the uh-oh moment."
当一些特定的小事发生时
When a certain little something happens,
你会明白那是结局的开始
and you know you've just witnessed the beginning of the end.
然后你会兴致全无 并且去思考
And suddenly you stop and you think:
"啊 冰山就在前面"
"Uh-oh, iceberg ahead."
和尼基一起 这只是那些"阿呃时刻"的
With Nikki, that was the first of many...
第一次
...uh-oh moments.
大多是琐事引起争吵
It began with petty arguments.
然后是间歇性的忧郁
Followed by random bouts of melancholia.
无比的兴奋 狂躁的低迷
Major highs and manic lows.
这个女孩从不知道当她过分地拥有一个男人
This girl never knows when she's had one too many.
并且持续出现不稳定的卤莽行为时
And there had been constant displays of erratic, reckless behaviour.
谢谢 不 不 我无法保证会和她走到最后
And thank you, no. No, I did not have insurance.
但是每次当我开始感觉到 没有必要再继续下去了的时候
But whenever I begin to feel there's little reason to go on,
我还是会提醒自己 我们仍然有很多共同点
I'm reminded that we still have one very major thing in common.
若然 她不再无时无刻地吸烟
If only she didn't insist on smoking before,
未来
after
以及现在
and during.
你何时回家 亲爱的
What time are you gonna be home, honey?
听到了吗
Hear that?
"你何时回家 亲爱的"
"What time are you gonna be home, honey?"
这些近似妻子口吻的话是危险十足的
That's dangerously close to wife-speak to me.
因为我为"晚特餐"做特别的准备
Because I'm making something really special for din-din.
"晚特餐"
Din-din?
我等会打电话回来
I'll call later.
听着 你不觉得那颜色有点太刺眼了吗
Listen, are you sure you don't think that colour's a little bit intense?
－我觉得你有点太显眼了 －小心
－I think you're a little bit intense. －Careful,
你手上都是油漆
because you've got paint all over your hands.
而且 你穿着我最喜欢的衬衫在粉刷房间 尼基 别这样
Plus, you're wearing my favourite shirt to paint the house in, Nik. Don't...
抱歉 亲爱的
Sorry, baby.
我要走了
I gotta run.
不 我要走了
No, I've gotta run.
我打赌我能让你多呆一会
I bet that I can make it worth your while to stay.
我知道你能 但是知道吗 我要去接人
I'm sure you can. But you know what? I've got that meeting.
－知道吗 －是的
－Haven't I? －Yeah.
你知道 当像那样一个讯号 没能把你留住 你得小心了
You know you're in trouble when a sight like that can't keep you planted.
当我还在圣.阿尔班念高中时
When I was a boy at St. Alban's Secondary School,
学校组织了一次文化之旅
the school took us on this cultural trip
去了一个
to observe art at one of the...
很大很著名的伦敦博物馆
One of those big famous London museums.
总之 当时我在那里
Anyway, when I was there,
看到一尊希腊女神的大理石像时
I came across this statue of a Greek goddess in marble.
阿芙罗荻...阿芙罗荻特 诸如此类的
Aphrodi... Aphrodite, something like that.
她漂亮极了
Beautiful, she was.
完美的女性胴体
Perfect female form.
雕凿的特征
Chiselled features.
精美无比
Exquisite.
我敬畏地望着她
I stood in awe of her.
最后 老师叫我们集合了 我经过雕塑
Finally, the teacher calls us all over, and I'm walking past it,
与此之际 我留意到女神像的侧面
and on the way I notice, in the side of this Greek goddess,
所有的那些裂缝 缺口 瑕疵
all these cracks, chips, imperfections.
毁了我对她的美好印象
Ruined her for me.
就像尼基
Well, that's Nikki.
一尊美丽的雕像
A beautiful sculpture...
毁了
...damaged...
当然 只有你走近了 才能看仔细
...in a way you don't notice till you get too close.
我对着那个信号茫然了一会
I lost the signal for a second there.
但我不知道
But I don't know.
这只是个人的思绪翻滚而已
It's just a lot of personal stuff going on.
你明白我吗
You know what I mean?
－哦 我知道 －欢迎 阿尔菲先生
－Oh, I know. －Welcome, Mr Alfie.
很高兴见到你 埃尔维司 希望你不介意我进去
Good to see you, Elvis. Look, I hope you don't mind me rambling on.
－祝你愉快 先生 －谢谢
－Enjoy your evening, sir. －Thank you.
如你所见 这小子的地位提高了
As you can see, the lad's moving up in the world.
事实是我认识了一个朋友
It's just that I've got this friend who's,
这么说吧 死赖着不走
let's say, outstayed his welcome.
完全正确
Absolutely right.
有些人易请难送啊 我喜欢
It's a lot tougher getting them out than getting them in. I like that.
你永远无法猜到我正要拜访谁
You'll never guess who I'm dropping in on now.
几周前我都无法相信
I wouldn't have believed it myself a couple of weeks ago.
你为什么不直接告诉他们
Why don't you just try being honest,
酒店要调整管理 注入新血
and tell your friend that the hotel is under new management
他们得腾出几个位子 你懂我的意思
and that they have to vacate the premises. You know what I mean.
那件和服
That kimono
因为你的低胸衣而美妙
does wonders for your decolletage.
－大话 －很低的领口啊
－Big word. －Big decolletage.
我们为何不喝一杯 然后告诉我你其他的麻烦
Why don't we have a drink and you can tell me the rest of your troubles.
变成我听她的话 转型了
Instead of me listening to hers. That's a change.
知道嘛 对很年轻的人来说 你极富智慧
You know, for someone so very young, you're terribly wise.
暗恋者?
Secret admirer?
其中之一
One of many.
你永远不会送花给女孩子 是吗 阿尔菲
You would never think of bringing a girl flowers, would you, Alfie?
这只会鼓励他们
It would only encourage them.
我去拿酒
I'm gonna make us that drink.
你喜欢喝什么 亲爱的
What's your poison, sweetheart?
我想喝一点威士忌 谢谢 如果你有精品米尔顿的话
I'll have a spot of whiskey, please. Midleton Rare, if you've got it.
我喜欢不时地抛出一些名贵的品牌
I like dropping a fancy brand name in now and again,
让她知道 她不是我唯一的女人
let her know she ain't the only one been around.
为何不把这个制做成"午后苦艾酒"
Why not make this an absinthe afternoon?
太好了
Brilliant.
－不知道她在说什么 －你喝过苦艾酒吗
－No idea what she's talking about. －You've had absinthe?
最近没有 不 没有 再说一遍 叫什么
Not recently, no. Remind me, what is it again?
绿仙女 法国印象派的液体毒品
The Green Fairy. The French impressionists' liquid drug of choice.
我还给你准备了你喜欢的小蛋塔
And I got you some of those little egg thingies you like so much.
我提过我一旦喜欢上什么 接下来我就会
I mention I like something once, next thing I know,
把它放在银色托盘里
I get it on a silver platter.
完美 是吧
Perfect, huh?
买这种坐垫得花我一天的工资
Kind of pad I plan to earn myself one day.
简朴优雅 略带一点时髦的格调
Understated elegance with just a touch of the trendy.
她是个时尚疯狂追随者
She's a regular fashionista.
你不必跟她说哪件外套配哪双鞋
You don't have to tell this one which slingbacks go with which frock.
她拥有自己的化妆品牌公司
Owns her own cosmetics company.
事实上 化妆品帝国
Empire, actually.
从在时尚沙龙做面部美容产品起家
Started out doing facials in a fancy salon.
用一点洗颜泥和少许番木瓜混合
Took a handful of mud, mixed it with a dash of papaya,
然后投放到市场 成事 就这么简单
put it on the market, and bingo: All this.
这些东西都是违法的
This stuff is so illegal.
我从布拉格走私了一批
I smuggled a whole batch of it back from Prague
装在李斯特林瓶里
in Listerine bottles.
哦 我看了下你的工作计划
Oh, I checked out your business plan.
－然后呢 －印象深刻
－And? －I'm impressed.
－你看上去很惊讶 －一点也不
－You seem surprised. －Not at all.
因为在这些虚张声势下
Because underneath all that bravado
要打败一个比想象中聪明的家伙
beats the heart of a guy who's a lot smarter than he thinks he is,
但他不会像人们想象的那么骄傲
but not nearly as cocky as he'd like everybody else to believe.
我们这是算什么呢  算是建立在哪种基础上呢
What are we...? What exactly are we basing this on?
这种对我人格的剖析
This insight into my personality
将心比心
That it takes one to know one.
什么
What?
我在想如果有一个机灵的小纹身艺术家在这的话
I was just wondering if there's a clever little tattoo artist out there
他可以把"巴布罗"改成"阿尔菲"
who could change "Pablo" into "Alfie."
敬聪明的小纹身艺术家
Here's to clever little tattoo artists.
天啊
Jesus.
我觉得一股热流在往下
It made me feel all warm going down.
那是我做的
That's my job.
你知道他们说什么吗
You know what they say.
说什么
What do they say?
苦艾酒能让情更浓
Absinthe makes the heart grow fonder.
哦 太好了
Oh, great.
瞧瞧这
Check this out.
再看看浴缸的尺寸
Have a look at the size of this tub.
她有过两个丈夫 都死了
She's had two husbands, both croaked,
我有种感觉 这里就是犯罪现场
and I have a feeling this was the scene of the crime.
来 亲爱的 洗个鸳鸯浴吧
Come on, baby, let's get wet.
如果她继续这样
If she keeps this up,
改变那个纹身会比她想象中快得多
we're gonna be updating that tattoo of hers a lot sooner than she thinks.
记得小阿尔菲最后是怎样得到他想要的圣诞礼物的吗
Remember how little Alfred finally got what he wanted for Christmas?
期望值别太高
Be careful what you wish for.
还有其他
There's something else.
打盹了吗
Dozed off?
是啊
Yeah.
我想要醒着等你的
I tried waiting up for you.
－接待拖了很长时间 是吧  - 非常久 我筋疲力尽了
－Your meeting ran late, huh? －Very. I'm knackered.
还淋湿了
And wet.
但是
But...
我想我们还是应该谈谈 尼基
...I do want us to have a little chat, Nikki.
好啊
Okay.
当然
Sure.
为什么不谈谈夜宵呢
Why don't we talk over a midnight snack.
我做了烤牛肉和约客郡布丁
I made roast beef and Yorkshire pudding.
那是你小时侯的最爱是吗
That was your favourite as a young lad, right?
来吧 过来看看吧
And check the place out, if you please.
－你的小姑娘辛苦劳作了一番 －我留意到了 看起来很好
－Your little girl worked her fanny off. －I noticed. It looks brilliant.
做得很棒
Really smashing.
－尼基 －阿尔菲 我在想
－So, Nik... －Alfie, I've been thinking.
你瞧这些可爱的小土豆了吗
Will you look at these cute little potatoes?
是 我知道我最近脾气不好
Okay. I know I have been a real handful lately.
我不知道 这和我不放心你
I don't know, I think it has to do a lot with me feeling displaced...
不完全信任你有关
...and not totally trusting.
亲爱的 直入正题吧
Sweetie, cutting to the chase.
我不再发脾气
I am gonna do better.
我保证
I promise.
从现在开始起我会按时吃药治疗
I am gonna take my medication religiously from now on.
一切都会好起来的
And everything, everything is gonna be easy and breezy.
听上去不错吧 亲爱的
Sound good? Honey?
来 过来坐啊 等着你开餐
So come, come and sit. A feast awaits.
我吃过了 尼基
I already ate, Nik.
那好
Of course.
不用担心 就当是把剩菜放起来
No worries, we'll have leftovers.
我可以放点牛肉当饭吃
I can whip up a little corned beef hash for brunch.
怎么了 阿尔菲
What's the matter, Alfie?
没什么 我只是...
Nothing. I just...
我脑子很乱...
I've got a lot on my mind and...
－我觉得有点... －什么
...I'm feeling a bit... －What?
冷漠 距离 疏远 还有什么
Cold? Distant? Remote? What?
哦 尼基这一切都是胡扯
Oh, Nik, this is a complete drag.
一切发生的太快了
Everything happened so quickly.
－我在这方面不合适 －哪方面
－I'm not the best at this sort of thing. －What sort of thing?
我...
I...
不知道该怎么说
...don't know exactly how to say it.
当然能说 阿尔菲
Sure you do, Alfie.
甩女孩子你很有经验
You've had plenty of experience dumping girls.
别担心
Don't worry.
我早打算走了
I'm already gone.
真是奇怪
Strange.
即使你知道感情走到头了...
But even when you know it has to end...
但当这一切真的结束时...
...when it finally does...
你还是无法避免地感到痛苦
...you always get that inevitable twinge?
我做的对吗
Have I done the right thing?
我必须承认...
I must admit...
我很怀念那种伴侣关系
...I do miss the companionship.
尼基是很惊艳
Nikki was a showstopper.
但是像我又老又丑的Gladys阿姨曾说的
But as me ugly old Aunt Gladys used to say,
外表不代表一切
"Looks aren't everything."
我以前觉得那根本只是胡说
I used to think that was a load of bollocks,
但是最近我一直在想...
but just lately I've been thinking...
...也许那个老太婆说的是对的
...maybe the old bat had something.
茱利?
Julie?
阿尔菲 嗨
Alfie, hi.
真没想到啊
What a surprise.
－天啊 我很久没见到你了 自从... －是啊
－God, I haven't seen you since... －Yeah.
你看上去真不错
You look... You look amazing.
谢谢 你也是 你看上去也很好
Thanks. You too. You look good too.
我感冒刚好
I'm getting over a cold.
－不过没事了 对吧 －我很好 我一直都很好
－But you're okay otherwise? －I'm fine. I'm always fine.
见到你很高兴
It's good to see you.
我也是
And you.
嗨 我以前...
Hey, you know, I was...
我很抱歉我们之间发生的那些事
I'm sorry about what happened between us.
也很遗憾我们之间那样结束了 这不...
And I'm sorry how it all ended up. It wasn't...
这不太妥当
It wasn't good.
麦克司走了 我也见不到你 我感觉差极了
I felt bad about not seeing Max and about not seeing you.
－往事如云 别提了 －挺好
－It's water under the bridge. －Good.
你知道
You know...
我在想...
...I'm wondering...
也许我们...
Maybe we...
我不能保证什么
You know I can never promise anything.
但是你愿意 如果你愿意
But if you want, if you like,
也许我们可以从新开始
maybe we could see each other again.
我觉得可以
It would be okay by me.
不是可以 是很乐意
It would be more than okay, it would be great.
－阿尔菲 我... －怎么
－Alfie, l... －Yeah?
这是亚当
This is Adam.
嗨 你好
Hey, how are you?
－嗨 你好 亚当 －好啊
－Hey, how you doing, Adam? －Pretty good.
－亚当 －是啊
－Adam. －Yeah.
遇见你太好了
It was great running into you.
－你看上去很棒 －谢谢
－You look fantastic. －Thanks.
几点了 我得走了
What time is it? I've gotta go.
我有个接待要迟到了 很高兴见到你 亚当
I'm late for a meeting. Nice to meet you, Adam.
茱利
Julie
－麦克司好吗 －哦 很好
－How's Max? －Oh, really good.
替我问好
Will you say hi?
－好的 －或者不必了
－Sure. －Or not.
保重
Be well.
嗨
Hello.
闻太太 一切还...
Mrs Wing, is everything...?
闻先生
Wing.
你怎么哭了
Why are you crying?
我没哭 出去
I'm not crying. Get out.
－你确定吗 －我没事 出去 阿尔菲
－You sure? －I'm fine. Get out, Alfie.
抱歉 我只是想看看能否借辆车
I'm sorry. I just wanted to see if I could borrow a car.
她离开我了
She leave me.
什么
Sorry?
如花 她走了
Blossom leave me.
如花 那是你太太的名字吗 如花
Blossom? Is that your wife's name, Blossom?
我做错什么了 阿尔菲  因为爱她吗
What I do wrong, Alfie? Love her?
瞧 老兄 快点 你能找回她的
Look, mate. Come on, you can win her back.
哄哄她 给她送花 巧克力
Woo her. Send flowers and chocolates.
写诗
Write a poem.
－你这么做的吗 －事实上 不 我从没做过
－That what you do? －Well, actually, no, I've never done that,
但是那应该可行
but it may be a way to go.
如花押什么韵
What rhyme with Blossom?
我会用 无瑕
I would try "awesome."
好
Okay.
你总是带来惊喜从不间断
You never cease to amaze.
嗨
Hey.
很高兴见到你 洛
Great to see you too, Lon.
我应该打电话来的 嗨 山姆
I guess I should have rung. Hey, Sam.
恩 事先知会一下更好
Well, that would have been a plan.
哦 抱歉 我只是
Well, you know, I'm sorry, it was just...
不错啊
It's nice.
瞧 洛内特
Look, Lonette...
这真是很尴尬 你瞧 因为
This is so uncomfortable, I know. Because...
你不必那么小声 马龙不在
You don't have to whisper. Marlon's not here.
我真的很怀念你们俩
I really miss you both.
我刚刚在想 也许 ...
And I just wondered, maybe...
也许我和你可以忘了以前的一切
Maybe me and you could put it all behind us,
当作什么事都没发生 像从前那样 你知道吗
pretend like it never happened, and then move forward, you know?
我只是
I just...
你知道的 阿尔菲
You know, Alfie...
忘却不是一个好办法
...dropping by wasn't a good idea.
你们俩没有孩子
You two didn't have a baby.
你们有孩子
You did have a baby.
不 你前面那一句是对的(言指孩子是阿尔菲的)
No, you were right the first time.
回想起那天在诊所 我记得
Thinking back to that day at the clinic, I remember
我想要从洛内的眼中看出 我是否能理解她
trying to look in Lon's eyes to see if I could even begin to understand
看她经历了什么 但她并不愿看着我
what she was going through, and how she wouldn't look at me.
我想那时我是知道的
And I think I knew then.
我只是不愿承认而已
I just didn't want to admit it to myself.
所以
So classically...
...我沉默不语
...I said nothing.
我知道这孩子还是有可能
I knew there was a good chance the baby
是马龙的
could be Marlon's.
至少我那么想过
At least, I hoped.
对我而言...
This is a lot...
我也很希望 洛
...for me too, Lon.
马龙选择留下
Marlon stayed.
现在是吧
For now.
我能补偿什么吗
Is there anything I can do?
你又可以补偿什么 阿尔菲
What are you gonna do, Alfie?
嗨
Hey.
你知道 我从没...
You know, I never...
－我从没想过... －你从没想过伤害任何人
－I never meant... －You never mean to hurt anybody.
但你做到了 阿尔菲
But you do, Alfie.
我想我需要有个朋友倾诉
I felt I needed a friend to talk to.
问题是 突然之间却找不到了
Problem was, they were suddenly in short supply.
我不记得当时是否在车里 我只是...只是...我就停在那里
And I don't remember being in the car. I just... I just... I was stopped.
然后我哭了
And I'm crying.
－为那个孩子哭吗 －事实上 我也不知道
－Crying for the little one? －I don't know exactly.
也许是吧
Maybe for him.
我想 更多的是为我和
Mostly, I think, for me.
马龙的友情
And Marlon.
从未有人像那样的看着我
I never had anybody look at me quite like that before.
相信我 我感觉他恨死我了
And believe me, I've had some looks that could kill.
他站在洛内迪旁边 我没有 从没有...
He stood by Lonette. I could've never, ever...
你不会明白你想要什么 除非你真正爱上了一个人
You don't know what you'll do till you really love someone.
那 接下来呢
Well, now what?
你会重新振作吗
You gonna shoehorn yourself into the situation?
不
No.
你做了你唯一能做的 你表现的像个绅士
You did the only thing you could do. You behaved like a gentleman.
我从没被人那样指责
I've never been accused of that before.
别说的那么伟大 你的行为也不怎么光彩
Don't get all choked up. You also behaved like a scheming,
背后捅刀子 卑鄙无耻 狗娘养的
backstabbing, so-low-you-can-look-up-a-snake's-asshole son of a bitch.
下次拉裤链时 要三思
Next time, think before unzipping.
没事了 你已经搞砸了
It's all right. You screwed up.
那么 接下来你要做什么
So, what are you gonna do?
解决问题吗
Run to the bridge?
问题是...
The question is...
... 你的余生会怎样呢
...what's gonna happen with the rest of your life?
如果我说已经忘了上几个周发生的事
I'd be lying if I didn't admit the events of the past few weeks
那我肯定是在撒谎
have knocked me for a bit of a loop.
好啦 好啦 好啦
All right, all right, all right.
嗨 伙计
Hello, mate.
今晚要些什么
And what can we do for you this evening?
－这个多少钱 －五块半
－How much are one of those? －Five-fifty.
你要马上放到水里
And you'll need to put them in water immediately.
好的 我要这个
Right, I'll have that.
还有个想法
Second thought.
事实上 有点特别
Actually, this is sort of a special thing.
－什么场合 －再说一遍
－What's the occasion? －Say again?
－求婚吗 －不 不是
－Proposal? －No. No, no.
也许 我想是有那么一丝目的
Well, I do want to extend an offer to maybe have a go at it for a bit,
增进一下感情 诸如此类
give us a spin, that kind of thing.
知道了 表白！
I get it. Commitment issues.
告诉我 她或他是怎么样的人
Tell me what she, or he, is like,
我们会找到合适的花的
and we'll find the appropriate bloom.
恩 她是...
Well, she is...
你知道吗 她很爱冒险
You know what, she's adventurous.
－浮华 －而且非常性感
－Frivole. －And very sexy.
我想选"美好人生"吧
I'm thinking Dolce Vita.
有点调皮 不拘礼节
A little mischievous. You know, cheeky?
极致诱惑 再配上
Avalanche, with a touch
爱慕之情
of mio amore.
除此之外 更多的是...
And then under it all, she's just...
她的甜美
She's just kind of sweet.
利滋?
Liz?
－嗨 －是我 亲爱的
－Hello? －It's me, my love.
嗨 我没想到你今晚回来 我以为你在工作
Hey, I didn't expect to see you tonight. I thought you were working.
我取消了 所以我今晚有空
I had a cancellation, so I took the night off.
听着 我想我们可以早点起来 然后离开城市
Listen, I thought we should get up early, get out of the city,
到乡间去 看看我们是否能
go to the country and see if we can stay
－住在你常提到的B&B酒店 －我很乐意 但是我不能
－at that B&B you're always on about. －I'd love to, but I can't.
明天早上我要和投资人吃早餐谈生意
I have an investors' breakfast in the morning.
－周末呢 －太好了 那样更好
－How about on the weekend? －Brilliant. Better.
好吧 我想你也许...
All right. I thought you may...
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
不是吧 阿尔菲
No. Alfie.
－哦 多么贴心的示意 －亲爱的
－Oh, what a sweet gesture. －Milady.
这可不是那些行货 都是我精挑细选的
They're not out of some plastic bucket. I handpicked, like, every bud.
－我看得出来 －而且我看上去还是有那么点
－I can see that. －And apparently, I have a bit of a flair
组合鲜花的天赋
for flower arranging.
我太感动了
I'm impressed.
－都说不出话了 －很好 哄你开心我做到了
－Talk about being blown away. －Good. Mission accomplished.
我喜欢给你惊喜
I like surprising you.
恩 你的确做到了
Well, you certainly have done that.
那么 既然你要早起 那我走了
All right, then. Well, you're up early, so I'm off.
－我们明晚见 对吗 －是的
－I'm gonna see you tomorrow night? －Yeah.
我们见面时 有些事...
When we speak, there's some things...
有些事我想认真和你谈谈
Some thing I really wanna talk to you about.
什么 亲爱的
What, honey?
我要等到那完美的一刻才说 先透露着这么些
I'm gonna wait for the exact perfect moment, and that's all I'll say.
我明早给你电话
I'll ring you in the morning.
阿尔菲 谢谢你的花 我今晚乐极了
And, Alfie, thank you for the flowers. They made my evening.
真的吗
Really?
既然这样 也许我应该留下
In that case, maybe I'll stay.
我不想...
I don't...
不要 这不太好
No, it's not a good idea.
有男人在房间里 是吗
There's a guy in there, isn't there?
天啊
God...
走吧
Go.
别这样
Don't do this.
他哪里
What's he got
－比我好呢 －阿尔菲 求你
－Better than me? －Alfie, please.
告诉我 求你了
Tell me. Please?
真的 我真想知道 他哪里好 告诉我
Really, I would like to know. What's he got? Tell me.
我想知道他哪里比我好 求你告诉我
I want to know what he's got. Please tell me.
来啊 来 来 马上告诉我
Come on. Come on. Come on, just tell me.
马上告诉我 说啊
Just tell me, come on.
他哪里比我好!!!
What's he got better than me?!
他比你年轻
He's younger than you.
"他比你年轻"
"He's younger than you."
我必须承认 我没预料到这个
I've gotta admit, I didn't see it coming.
她让我毫无防备 不是吗
She caught me off-guard, all right.
你也说不清 是吗
You couldn't tell, though, could you?
如同你现在看到的 我宁愿若无其事一样
As you've learned by now, I'm rather skilled at hiding my feelings.
你瞧 爱情这玩意
You see, the thing with feelings is they have
当你始料不及之际 它静静地闯进你的生活
this quiet way of sneaking up on you when you least expect it.
你懂我意思吗
You know what I mean?
是的
Yeah.
就像利滋
Like with Liz.
谁会想到 在所有我认识的女人中
Who would've thought, of all the women I've known...
这个让我放下防备的 却给了我致命的一击
...the one I let my guard down with delivers the knockout punch.
讽刺
Ironic.
日历上的话
Calendar word.
桃利
Dorie.
－嗨 －嗨 阿尔菲
－Hi. －Hello, Alfie.
－我很久没见你了 －也许是你很久没打电话给我了
－I haven't seen you in ages. －Maybe because you stopped calling.
我知道 事情变得有些
I know. Things were getting a bit too...
别费心解释了 我不想听解释了
Don't bother explaining. I'm way past needing excuses.
好吧 不 你知道我想说什么吗
All right. No, you know what? I want to explain.
什么 你玩厌我了吧
What? You had your fill of me?
又遇到了比我漂亮的吗 我不想听 阿尔菲
Someone cuter came along? I don't need to hear it, Alfie.
－瞧 桃利 －真的
－Look, Dorie... －Really.
瞧 桃利
Look, Dorie...
发生在我身上的是...
What happens with me is...
我不知道 我变得...
I don't know, I get...
当一切变得...不是指亲密 就是之类的事
When it gets too... Not close but something like that,
我开始觉得  不是喘不过气
I start to feel... Not stifled,
不是被束缚了 好吧 类似这样的感觉
not trapped, but something like that.
然后我...然后..
And I... And...
你知道 你懂我意思吗
You know? You know what I mean?
这会....这会意味点什么吗
Did that make...? Did that make any sense?
我想 你现在应该比我更明白这点
I think it has to make sense to you more than me at this point.
是啊 很公平
Yeah, fair enough.
我要走了 他等着我呢
I need to go. He'll be waiting for me.
桃利
Dorie.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
祝你好运 阿尔菲
Good luck, Alfie.
我从一开始就警告她们
I warned them all from the beginning.
我总是这么说
I always said something along the lines of,
我必须提醒你
"I must advise you,
我始终坚持着一个忠告
I am stamped with an invisible warning.
我永不忠诚于一 我永不结婚
I will not commit. I will never marry."
尽管我尽力了 我还是开始感到有点内疚悔意
Despite my best efforts, I'm beginning to feel some small cracks
因为我的始乱终弃
in my faux finish.
当我回首生活的点滴时
You know, when I look back on my little life,
以及那些我认识的所有女人
and all the women I've known...
...我不禁想
...I can't help but think about...
...她们为我所做的一切...
...all that they've done for me...
...而我却只付出极少
...and how little I've done for them.
她们那么关心我 爱我...
How they looked after me, cared for me...
可我却从未回报过她们
...and I repaid them by never returning the favour.
是啊
Yeah.
我过去常想 我有着最好的分手方式
I used to think I had the best end of the deal.
我到底得到了什么
What have I got? Really?
有几个臭钱
Some money in my pocket.
名牌服饰 有辆炫车
Some nice threads. Fancy car at my disposal.
和单身生活
And I'm single.
无拘无束 像小鸟般自由
Unattached. Free as a bird.
不依赖任何人
I don't depend on nobody.
也没人依赖我
Nobody depends on me.
一个人过着生活
My life's my own.
但心里不踏实
But I don't have peace of mind.
如果你不是那样想 你便一无所有
And if you don't have that, you've got nothing.
所以
So...
所以 什么才是答案呢 我不断问自己
So, what's the answer? That's what I keep asking myself.
意义又何在呢
What's it all about?
你懂我意思吗
You know what I mean?
==春秋字幕组荣誉出品==
= www.cqbbs.net =